<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forecasting on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/tags/forecasting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Forecasting on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/forecasting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Regime Switching Model</title>
      <link>/2016/07/29/regime-switching-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/07/29/regime-switching-model/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a sucker for statistical methods and Machine Learning particularly anything with a cool sounding name. When reading about Crouching Tiger Hidden Markov Models in an earlier post I stumbled across a topic called regime detection.
In economics latent Markov models, are so called Regime switching models. Regime Detection comes in handy when you are trying to decide which strategy to deploy. For example there are periods (regimes) when Trend Following strategies, like an autoregressive integrated moving average model (ARIMA) or exponential smoothing state space models (ETS) forecasting work better and there are periods when other strategies might be better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting virtual hat sales in Dota 2</title>
      <link>/2016/04/24/predicting-virtual-hat-sales-in-dota-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/04/24/predicting-virtual-hat-sales-in-dota-2/</guid>
      <description>{% include _toc.html %}
{% highlight r %} #LIBRARY - check if packages are installed and load them library(dplyr) library(rvest) library(zoo) library(forecast) {% endhighlight %} &amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Prediction is very difficult, especially if it&amp;rsquo;s about the future.&amp;rdquo; - Niels Bohr
As a scientist I&amp;rsquo;m experienced in designing controlled experiments to produce tidy dataframes. Ideally we end up with each row in the dataframe representing a unique observation at the level of the experimental unit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>