<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Feature Selection on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/tags/feature-selection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Feature Selection on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/feature-selection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic programming in space</title>
      <link>/2016/11/14/genetic-programming-in-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/14/genetic-programming-in-space/</guid>
      <description>Genetic Programming (GP) is a collection of techniques from evolutionary computing (EC) for the automatic generation of computer programs that perform a user-defined task. Starting with a high-level problem definition, GP creates a population of random programs that are progressively refined through variation and selection until a satisfactory solution is found. A lack of foresight does not prevent this blind watchmaker from arriving at a sensible design solution for modelling the data as demonstrated in this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sold!</title>
      <link>/2016/10/23/sold/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/23/sold/</guid>
      <description>There seems nothing the British press likes more than a good house price story. Accordingly we use the Kaggle dataset on house prices as a demonstration of the data science workflow. With 79 explanatory variables describing (almost) every aspect of residential homes in Ames, Iowa, this competition challenges you to predict the final price of each home (every dataset has a story, see here for details). I found this dataset particularly interesting, as it informs someone new to he housing market as to what variables one should ask questions about if one were to buy a house.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>