<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/tags/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statistics on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nearest neighbour methods</title>
      <link>/2016/05/27/nearest-neighbour-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/05/27/nearest-neighbour-methods/</guid>
      <description>{% include _toc.html %}
In my last post, I started working through some examples given by Hastie et al in Elements of Statistical learning. I looked at using a linear model for classification across a randomly generated training set. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll use nearest neighbour methods to create a non-linear decision boundary over the same data.
Nearest neighbour algorithm There are much more learned folk than I who give good explanations of the maths behind nearest neighbours, so I won&amp;rsquo;t spend too long on the theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting to grips with &#39;Elements of statistical learning&#39;</title>
      <link>/2016/05/08/getting-to-grips-with-elements-of-statistical-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/05/08/getting-to-grips-with-elements-of-statistical-learning/</guid>
      <description>{% include _toc.html %}
Last week I joined a reading group for the weighty tome Elements of Statistical Learning. I really like the idea of this group; interesting as it is - it can be hard to maintain the drive to wade through a text like this. Working through it week on week with a group of like-minded people is a great way to overcome this.
Linear models In this post I implement in R some of the ideas that are presented in the first 2 chapters of Elements of Statistical Learning, namely: least squares.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>