<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Education on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/tags/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Education on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting to grips with &#39;Elements of statistical learning&#39;</title>
      <link>/2016/05/08/getting-to-grips-with-elements-of-statistical-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/05/08/getting-to-grips-with-elements-of-statistical-learning/</guid>
      <description>{% include _toc.html %}
Last week I joined a reading group for the weighty tome Elements of Statistical Learning. I really like the idea of this group; interesting as it is - it can be hard to maintain the drive to wade through a text like this. Working through it week on week with a group of like-minded people is a great way to overcome this.
Linear models In this post I implement in R some of the ideas that are presented in the first 2 chapters of Elements of Statistical Learning, namely: least squares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The magic of neural networks</title>
      <link>/2016/04/10/the-magic-of-neural-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/04/10/the-magic-of-neural-networks/</guid>
      <description>{% include _toc.html %}
Education is a key factor affecting long term economic progress. Success in the core subjects provide a linguistic and numeric scaffold for other subjects later in students&amp;rsquo; academic careers.The growth in school educational databases facilitates the use of Data Mining and Machine Learning practises to improve outcomes in these subjects by identifying factors that are indicative of failure (or success). Predicting outcomes allows educators to take corrective measures for weak students mitigating the risk of failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing classifier performance</title>
      <link>/2016/03/24/assessing-classifier-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/03/24/assessing-classifier-performance/</guid>
      <description>{% include _toc.html %}
Introduction  Actual class values
 Predicted class values
 Estimated probability of the prediction
  These are three main types of data that are used to evaluate a classifier. We have used the first two types in previous blogs where we constructed a confusion matrix to compare the actual class values and the predicted class when applying the trained model on the test data with a support vector machines classifier model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logistic regression for student performance prediction</title>
      <link>/2016/03/15/logistic-regression-for-student-performance-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/03/15/logistic-regression-for-student-performance-prediction/</guid>
      <description>{% include _toc.html %}
Introduction Classification problems occur often, perhaps even more so than regression problems. Consider the Cortez student maths attainment data discussed in previous posts. The response variable, final grade of the year (range 0-20), G3 can be classified into a binary pass or fail variable called final, based on a threshold mark. We used a decision tree approach to model this data before which provided 95% accuracy and had the benefit of interpretability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lookup tables</title>
      <link>/2016/03/13/lookup-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/03/13/lookup-tables/</guid>
      <description>{% include _toc.html %}
Character matching provides a powerful way to make lookup tables. There are more concise functions available in packages like dplyr that achieve the same end but it is useful to understand how they are implemented with basic subsetting.
{% highlight r %} library(dplyr) {% endhighlight %}
We start off by building an example dataframe.
{% highlight r %} set.seed(1337) # we use rnorm
pupil_data &amp;lt;- data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student performance in Portugal</title>
      <link>/2016/03/01/student-performance-in-portugal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/03/01/student-performance-in-portugal/</guid>
      <description>{% include _toc.html %}
Education is a key factor affecting long term economic progress. Success in the core languages provide a linguistic and numeric scaffold for other subjects later in students&amp;rsquo; academic careers.The growth in school educational databases facilitates the use of Data Mining and Machine Learning practises to improve outcomes in these subjects by identifying factors that are indicative of failure. Predicting outcomes allows educators to take corrective measures for weak students mitigating the risk of failure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>