<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Arduino on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/tags/arduino/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Arduino on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/arduino/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi MQTT broker</title>
      <link>/2016/02/16/raspberry-pi-mqtt-broker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/02/16/raspberry-pi-mqtt-broker/</guid>
      <description>In my last post I started meddling with the ESP8266 module as a low cost (and smaller) alternative to an Arduino or Raspberry Pi for creating home sensors.
I was toying with the idea of sending measurements to a database using a RESTful API on the existing Postgres database I use to host measurements on Amazon Web Services.
After a bit of reading, I&amp;rsquo;ve realised that there is a better solution: MQTT, a lightweight protocol designed for machine to machine (M2M) communication for sensors, and similar low powered and simple devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IoT with the ESP8266</title>
      <link>/2016/02/01/iot-with-the-esp8266/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/02/01/iot-with-the-esp8266/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with Arduinos and Raspberry Pis (mostly the latter) for a couple of years now. I&amp;rsquo;ve mostly been interested in producing Wi-Fi enables sensors that can measure things like temperature, and electricity usage throughout the home. I&amp;rsquo;m currently part way through a number of posts in which I have been analysing a year&amp;rsquo;s worth of data collected using some of these sensors, in the last post I dealt with a year&amp;rsquo;s worth of [temperature measurements]().</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SylvaSense Part II</title>
      <link>/2015/08/01/sylvasense-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/08/01/sylvasense-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>Gypsum blocks In my previous post I was looking into building my own gypsum block soil moisture sensors. All the component parts have now arrived, and so I&amp;rsquo;ve now produced three sensors. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how I made them, show some preliminary data, and talk a bit about how much they cost.
I&amp;rsquo;m using 3 mm A3 stainless steel studding to form the electrodes across which the arduino will measure resistance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SylvaSense Part I</title>
      <link>/2015/07/28/sylvasense-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/07/28/sylvasense-part-i/</guid>
      <description>A bit of context I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing a lot with raspberry pis over the last couple of years. I&amp;rsquo;m now the proud owner of an original Raspberry Pi B, A, two A+s, and a brand spanking new Pi 2. Currently I have one sitting next to my electricity meter reading LED pulses from the meter, charting my electricity consumption, and a second running an external and internal temperature sensor, light, and humidity sensors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>