<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gender on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/tags/gender/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gender on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/gender/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Do women take the scenic route or do men cycle faster?</title>
      <link>/2014/11/16/do-women-take-the-scenic-route-or-do-men-cycle-faster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/11/16/do-women-take-the-scenic-route-or-do-men-cycle-faster/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post I started looking at the NY CitiBike data, and the differences between the way men and women use the service. It&amp;rsquo;s clear men use the service more, and that women&amp;rsquo;s journeys are generally longer; however it&amp;rsquo;s not clear if this is because they simply travel slower, or because they aren&amp;rsquo;t always taking the most direct route.
This is a difficult question to answer. Whilst it is easier to know whether the journey time from A to B is longer for men or women, it is not easy to know if the journey was direct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is CitiBike an old boy&#39;s club?</title>
      <link>/2014/11/02/is-citibike-an-old-boys-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/11/02/is-citibike-an-old-boys-club/</guid>
      <description>One of the first things you notice when drilling down into the New York Citibike data, is that there are a lot more male users than female. It&amp;rsquo;s quite a striking difference between the sexes, and has been picked up in the media. In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to look at the way Citibike usage differs across the sexes.
There are two types of Citibike users: long-term Subscribers to the service, and short term Customers who might only buy a weekly pass.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>