<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monitoring on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/tags/monitoring/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Monitoring on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/monitoring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring light with a Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>/2016/02/22/measuring-light-with-a-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/02/22/measuring-light-with-a-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>{% include _toc.html %}
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working through a year&amp;rsquo;s worth of sensor data that I collected using Raspberry Pis. In the last post on this subject I compared my temperature records with records from a local weather station. In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to look at the light measurements. I have two main questions I would like to answer:
 Can the light patterns be used to explain the temperature patterns noted in my temperature post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensing temperature with a Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>/2016/01/15/sensing-temperature-with-a-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/01/15/sensing-temperature-with-a-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>In my last post I started to delve into a year of sensor data that I have been collecting with my Raspberry Pi sensors. I made some general observations about the data, and went through the process of cleaning it.
In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll taking a deeper look at the temperature data. I currently have three temperatrue sensors: two internal (one a DS18B20, and a second within an DHT22 combined temperature and humidity sensor) and one external (another DS18B20).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring obsession</title>
      <link>/2015/12/24/measuring-obsession/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/12/24/measuring-obsession/</guid>
      <description>I like measuring things. There&amp;rsquo;s something about distilling life&amp;rsquo;s patterns into numbers which is deeply satisfying. I can&amp;rsquo;t explain it. But this is, at least in part, why I became a scientist.
About a year ago, I started exercising this obsession on my everyday life, and built a number of sensors out of Raspberry Pis to monitor the goings on in my house. This has variously fluctuated between one and three Pis, but at present I have two, one monitoring internal and external temperature, and internal light and humidity levels, and one measuring electricity usage by counting the pulses of the LED on my proprietary electricity meter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>